Kimbly!
Hey there.
Well?
I'm going to take revenge for what you did to Greed-san and my friends!
Kimbly-san,
what are you doing here?!
It shouldn't be that unusual,
considering I am a State Alchemist, right?
You sold us out and returned to the military! You're the worst!
Are you sure you want to let her kill me like this?
Martel-san, please stop!
What are you doing?!
Let go! Let go of me!
Are you all right?
Please stop!
Let go of me already!
You should make for some fine fireworks.
Martel-san!
Let go of me!
Kimbly-san, what are you doing to that man?!
I am, first and foremost, a soldier.
There's no reason why I should
bear the blame of some hooligan.
Martel-san!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
And here I was hoping to see a really exciting explosion...
But thanks to your interference...
Please don't lay a finger
on Martel-san.
By Martel, do you
mean this snake here?
Martel-san is a person!
I wasn't aware of that.
These guys are Chimeras.
They aren't even
full-fledged life forms!
Kind of like you.
You get away from Martel-san!
I'm not giving you
the chance to transmute!
Al...
Now!
To think that you'd be deliberately providing me with ingredients...
Martel-san!
Why, you monster...
Colonel...
He, like his brother,
is under my jurisdiction.
If you have any problems with him, you can file a written complaint.
Mark my words, I'm going to blow up that suit of armor.
You're going to the
frontlines yourself, Führer?
I won't let Liore
become another Ishbal.
Unless we bring an end to this quickly, with a minimum of casualties...
Y-Yes, of course.
I want you to take over
as acting Führer.
Y-You want me to?
Don't let me down.
Yes, sir!
Acting Führer! Acting Führer!
Oh, and sorry, but could you send something to my wife for me?
She gets lonely
all alone at home.
All right...
I'm counting on you.
Yes, sir!
Yet another city must fall...
for those who seek
the Philosopher's Stone.
If you've come this far, then you must know what my objective is.
Yeah.
You must be thinking of doing something foolish,
like creating a Philosopher's Stone.
I won't let you get in my way.
A Philosopher's Stone?
There's something I have to ask you.
Four years ago, back in Central,
did you see a Chimera that looked like a dog?
I sent it back to God.
Why would you do that?!
What else would you
have had me do?
That's not the kind of thing
that we should be deciding!
Is that all you have to say?
Do you plan on wiping out Rose and the other people of this city
with that same self-serving logic?!
You know Rose?
I'm going to open your eyes!
How?!
Don't you know?
You're an alchemist, after all.
I'm an alchemist?
Alchemy is comprised of
the three steps of comprehension, decomposition, and reconstruction.
You unconsciously read your
opponent's metallic composition
and then adjust your own technique to destroy it.
That's why I've been replacing the metal of my Automail
with other metals besides steel.
So that's it.
Of course, rapidly swapping around the metal in my Automail
is messing up its
delicate adjustments,
so I'm going to
put you down quick!
You dimwit!
Once you use the lives of this town's people
to make your Philosopher's Stone,
it will then be your turn to have vengeance taken against you!
Have you forgotten?
I can also destroy living flesh.
Homunculi?
Call me Lust, please.
I'm Gluttony!
You understand why we're telling you our names, right, Fullmetal Boy?
Yeah, you mean that today, we'll be saying good-bye.
Ah, that was hot!
Don't kill us off so casually, if you don't mind.
Like you did to Greed.
And here we were protecting you,
scarred man of Ishbal.
I am your enemy, am I not?
If you're going to create a Philosopher's Stone,
then we will protect you.
We won't let the boy interfere, either.
Do you recognize this?
It is something you gave my brother.
What are you talking about?
Remember!
Lust?
Lust!
I hate you! I hate you all!
What's the story between
you and that homunculus?
It's none of your business!
Wait!
Rose... and Lyra as well?!
"Please, listen to what
that man has to say, Ed."
That's what Rose-san
apparently wants to tell you.
Rose, you can't talk?
Keep it as a good-luck charm
so that even when I'm gone, you won't forget about me.
Back when Ishbal was still peaceful,
I had an older brother.
An intelligent brother, whom I was proud of
and whom was respected by everyone.
My brother had a beautiful girlfriend.
She fell ill,
and soon after, she was called home to Ishbala.
Brother, what are you searching for?
The Grand Art.
It's a hallowed endeavor that can bring all people back to life.
That's what those people from Central recently tried to promulgate here—
what they called alchemy—isn't it?
They say that
within the Grand Art,
there is a technique that
brings people back to life.
I see...
So that's it. That explains it.
Brother! Brother!
My brother defied the teachings of Ishbala in order to bring her back to life.
He lost part of his body.
And yet, she still
had not come back.
My brother was cast out.
The Grand Art was the greatest abomination in Ishbal, after all.
However, did my brother succeed after all?
That woman named Lust...
Do you know how
homunculi are born?
People conduct human transmutation and fail.
The botched product that is born at that time is a homunculus.
Come to mention it, I heard about that from Dante-san as well.
She said she once committed human transmutation
and had created a homunculus.
That could have been Greed.
But they shouldn't be able to survive very long as they are.
Someone is gathering up
homunculi like Lust and Envy,
giving them multiple lives, and controlling them.
Then Lust is the one
my brother created?
She doesn't have a soul.
She's just a monster that
has the same appearance.
Lust was affected by
this good-luck charm.
Homunculi have a weakness when
it comes to the remains of the person
who was the basis of their human transmutation.
Soon after my brother departed,
we were invaded for no reason.
We were angered by the
sudden attack and rose up.
And so, a long conflict began.
I've learned a way to create a Philosopher's Stone.
Brother!
If we were to possess its power,
we could save Ishbal
from its crisis.
In the middle of the war,
nobody rebuked
my brother for returning.
However, just as my brother was about to complete the Philosopher's Stone,
he suddenly renounced his research.
I now know the reason why.
I also heard the story,
from an outcast in Kishua.
It takes a large number
of human lives
to create a Philosopher's Stone using the Grand Art as well.
That's right.
It probably takes so many lives
that it would mean the destruction of a whole town, or a whole people.
Unless the frustration, malice,
and anger released at that time
all blend together,
a Philosopher's Stone
cannot be formed.
In order to save Ishbal,
we needed a Philosopher's Stone.
However, for that to happen,
Ishbal would have to be destroyed.
I am the State Alchemist in charge of the extermination of this district.
State Alchemist?
No more, please!
We have been driven from our land,
and we are fleeing.
Isn't that enough?
I was just told to exterminate you.
I am to stamp out every last one of you who has eyes and skin of a different color.
Why?!
Who knows?
A light bulb just
went off in my head.
I think I'll blow up your body, a little bit at a time.
First, I'll turn your skin
into an explosive.
Whoops...
Next will be this arm.
Now then, next will be...
That body of yours looks like a transmutation circle.
I didn't know there were any alchemists in Ishbal.
However, we have these
transmutation amplifiers.
Colonel Grand!
What the?
Brother!
I commit the lives of our people
within my body...
to you.
No! Brother, why did you do this?!
There is power within that arm.
If I had not done this,
you would be dead.
Brother... Brother!
I have done something
that cannot be forgiven.
You... liked her, didn't you?
Forgive me.
I am going on ahead... to see her, first...
Your brother was trying to transmute
a Philosopher's Stone inside his own body.
He took the lives of the dying Ishbalan people
and entrusted them to you, together with his own arm.
The Philosopher's Stone itself possesses power.
That's how I managed to hold on to my life.
That arm itself is an unfinished Philosopher's Stone.
That's why it reacts
with red stones.
It will take even more lives
to complete it.
Which is why you're setting Rose up
to be some charismatic leader
and manipulating
the people of Liore?!
Hold on!
Scar-san is not going to
sacrifice the people of Liore.
Lyra, what are you
even doing here?
After Dante-san passed away,
I searched for a place where
I could make my alchemy useful.
And then I learned
of Scar-san's plans.
Just before the fighting begins,
the people are going to flee through an underground passageway
that has been made
under the old church.
And then, the soldiers who have been lured into the city will be...
That means there will
still be casualties!
Besides, how is it
all right to kill soldi—
Do you know what
they've done in this town?
What did the military do to Rose?
She was taken into
the military's custody,
and when she came home, she had lost her speech.
Would you still ask us to forgive the military?
Martel-san, where are you?
This is a problem.
I want to go pick up Brother.
Havoc-san!
What's the matter?
Don't tell me there's an attack!
I don't know what's going on,
but I heard that the Führer has arrived.
It pleases me that the Führer himself would call for someone such as myself.
There is a matter of some secrecy that
I would like you two to lend me a hand with.
Lt. Col. Kimbly, I want you to take the lead of Tucker-kun's Chimeras and infiltrate the city.
I see, so you want us to run wild
and provoke them into attacking?
The same trick that we used in the fighting at Ishbal.
But even if we don't
go to all that trouble...
We will only act in order
to restore peace.
If they're the ones who start it,
we can say we're fighting for a just cause.
Also, there is still one
State Alchemist in Liore, right?
Edward Elric?
He has probably been killed. Find his body for me.
That will make our cause
even more just.
Even if I don't find his corpse,
I will see to it that he becomes one.
A shame that
we had to lose him.
I won't let you do it!
I won't let you do the same thing you did to Ishbal, nor will I let you kill Ed!
Come on, you're going to withdraw those orders!
Or else...
Your swift movements
will not work against me.
I have the Mightiest Eye, you see.
Ed! Al!
Al!
Martel-san!
Al, listen to me, and tell Ed, too!
Whatever, just get inside me!
Al, listen...
Are you okay, Alphonse-kun?
I have executed the Chimera that appeared to be threatening you.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 41: "Holy Mother"
I hear it—that voice...
That familiar voice, that was supposed to have been lost a long time ago...